Guide to the Antony E. Raubitschek Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Antony E. Raubitschek papers
1946-1955
SC1006
Raubitschek, A. E., (Antony Erich), 1912-1999
0.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Materials were the gift of the Bryn Mawr College Archives, 2010.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use.
Biographical/Historical note
At the time of his death in 1999, Antony E. Raubitschek was the Sadie Dernham Patek Professor of Humanities Emeritus and Professor Emeritus of Classics at Stanford University. Educated at the University of Vienna, he joined the Princeton Institute for Advanced Study in 1938 and taught at Yale before moving to Stanford in 1963 as Professor of Classics.
Scope and Contents note
This collection pertains to Raubitschek’s interest in Greek ostraka and the historical knowledge generated from their study; included in the collection are his historiography notes, correspondence, lists of ostraka, and photographs of ostraka. Correspondents include Eugene Vanderpool, C. W. J. Eliot, A. W. Gomme, James W. Alexander, Kurt Latte, and Kendrick Pritchett.
Access Terms
Alexander, James W.; Eliot, C. William J.; Gomme, A. W., (Arnold Wycombe); Latte, Kurt, 1891-1964.; Pritchett, Kendrick.; Vanderpool, Eugene, 1906-; Inscriptions, Greek.; Ostraka--Bibliography.; Ostraka.
Collection Contents
- Memorial Resolution by Stanford faculty on Antony E. Rautischek, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Historiography notes: A; includes letters from Eugene Vanderpool, 1954, and typescript paper “Das Datislied” (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Historiography notes: B-E; includes letters from Glenn [no last name on University of Pennsylvania letterhead], 1955, and C. W. J. Eliot, 1955; and typescript paper “Damon” in German (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Historiography notes: H-K; include typescript papers “Theopompos on Hyperbolos” and “The Recall of Cimon”; and letters from A. W. Gomme, 1954, and Ben [no last name on American Philological Association letterhead], 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Historiography notes: M; includes letters from C. W. J. Eliot, 1955, James W. Alexander (with copy of a paper), 1958, Kurt Latte (in German), 1954, and Eugene Vanderpool, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Historiography notes: N-S; includes letters from Gene [Vanderpool] 1953 and Kendrick Pritchett, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Historiography notes: T-X; includes correspondence between Raubitschek and Norman [no last name] in Augusta, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Historiography notes: miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 8)
- List of known ostraka (Box 1, Folder 9)
- The American Excavations in the Athenian Agora: Check List of Ostraka arranged by name and inventory number, 1946 Dec (Box 1, Folder 10)
- The American Excavations in the Athenian Agora: Ostraka: group lists, 1947 Feb (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Ostraka: List with hand-drawn illustrations, circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Ostraka: photographs (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Agora excavations, Athens: notes, illustrations, and photographs (Box 1, Folder 14)